### JOE C. KING III

3020 Oxford Glen Dr. Franklin, TN 37067 (865) 789-6607

jking0186@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/joe-king-iii-60b9a3173

github.com/jking0186

## **Summary**

A hard working and quick learning media professional moving online. Building on a decade of television production skills, I recently completed a full-time JavaScript coding cohort to learn about web development. Over 12 weeks, I was exposed to a full stack of development areas and found an interest in pursuing a front-end path.

#### **Coding competencies:**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Bootstrap

#### **Professional competencies:**

Video Editing, Camera Operation, On-Air Promotion, Branded Content. Additional strengths include creative problem-solving, written and verbal communication, and time management.

### **Education**

Vanderbilt University: Coding Bootcamp

**Southern New Hampshire University:** *Master of Arts in Communications/New Media & Marketing* **University of Tennessee:** *Bachelor of Science in Communications/Journalism & Electronic Media* 

# **Professional Experience**

### **Scripps Networks** | 2015 – 2019

Network Operations Technician (Dec. 2015 – Feb. 2019)

Focused on monitoring production networks, HGTV, Food Network, Travel Channel, DIY, Cooking Channel and GAC and assisting the Application Management team in troubleshooting issues. Responsible for ingesting and quality control of broadcast materials into all automation systems. Respond to known issues and preventing/resolving downtime and degradations in a prompt and efficient manner. Troubleshoot problems and recommend corrective action.

- Responsible for operating routers, patch bays, waveform monitors and encoding equipment.
- Work with product management, engineering, and development teams to find root causes and resolutions to improve equipment issues.

### Jewelry Television | 2010 - 2015

#### Director (Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2015)

Executed live show content as determined by the producing team to attain best revenue performance. Directed the live show team in all technical facets of the show. Focused on understanding the customer experience highlighting the product's positive attributes. Conducted production team reviews and evaluations of key members of each live show. Articulated sources of issues with defective equipment reports.

- Supervised production department, addressing performance and attendance concerns and mentoring new and experienced employees to demonstrate best practices with confidence.
- Enabled better shopping experience for customers by managing and delegating team roles based on strengths to execute a clean live show.

### Graphics Operator (Apr. 2011 – Aug. 2013)

Oversaw operation of graphics technology during live on-air shows. Ensured the accuracy and timely preparation of graphics assigned to productions while maintaining the quality of JTV's on-air product for daily/nightly broadcasts. Effectively identified and communicated technical problems. Worked closely and provided feedback to Directors and Producers ensuring quality and functionality of all graphics content.

- Kept the organization updated about new graphics software launched in the market
- Ensured proofing of graphics and made changes if required before going live on-air

#### Production Technician (Sep. 2010 – Apr. 2011)

Responsible for setting up and operating audio and visual equipment such as television cameras, audio board, and editing equipment. Calibrated audio and video equipment. Edit and prepare footage for playback from the Nexio video library. Record video and still camera shots inside and outside the studio. Edit short clips via Nexio and Final Cut Pro.

• Responsible for communicating directly with directors, producers, and production assistants to ensure a clean visual aesthetic for the live broadcast.

## UPS | 2004 - 2010

#### **Operations Supervisor**

Directed a team of 10 to provide exceptional customer service and exceed organizational expectations while observing air shipments ensuring freight arrived at destinations within company service standards. Managed and implemented security and loss prevention procedures. Prepared and managed safety procedures in accordance with Company, OSHA, and DOT guidelines, setting schedules, and preventing losses.